采访，梅西，巴萨，Take 5，Common Sticks，马克......
Interview, Messi, Barca, Take 5, Common Sticks, Marc...
如您所知，在这个项目中，Nou Clam，我们寻求......
As you know, in this program, the Nou Clam, we seek...
Como sabéis, en este programa, el Nou Clam, buscamos...
125周年纪念歌曲，我给大家带来了三首，大家可以听一下。
the 125th anniversary song and I have brought you three so that you can listen to them.
el canto del 125 aniversario y te he portado tres para que los escuches.
我们听一听可以吗？
Is it okay if we listen to one?
¿Te parece bien que escuchemos uno?
谷。
Vale.
为你聆听我的声音
for you listening to my voice
por tu escuchar mi voz
嗯，首先，祝贺您 125 周年。
Well, first of all, congratulate you on these 125 years.
Bueno, primero felicitarlo por estos 125 años.
告诉他，成为俱乐部的一员，成为……的球迷是一种荣幸。
tell him that it is an honor to be part of the club, to be a fan of...
decirle que es un orgullo ser parte del club, ser hincha de...
来自巴塞罗那。
from Barcelona.
de Barcelona.
我很幸运...
I was lucky that...
Tuve la suerte que...
上帝把我带到了这个地方，让我度过了一生。
that God took me to this place and made me spend my entire life.
que Dios me llevó hasta este lugar y me hizo pasar toda mi vida.
在那个美妙的俱乐部里。
in that wonderful club.
en ese maravilloso club.
一个特殊的俱乐部，与其他俱乐部不同，目前成为一名...
A special club, different from all, with how difficult it is at the moment to be a...
Un club especial, diferente de todos, con lo difícil que es en estos momentos ser un...
一个不同的俱乐部，因为当今足球界的处理方式以及它的变化。
a different club because of how things are handled today in football and because of how it changed.
un club diferente por cómo se manejan las cosas hoy en el fútbol y por cómo cambió.
今天的一切都按照我们想要的方式呈现，就像一线队一样......
Everything that today is represented the way we want and like the first team is...
Todo lo que hoy por hoy esté representado como nosotros queremos y nos gusta el primer equipo es...
这是一种巨大的自豪，我真的很想念俱乐部、这座城市、这里的人们、这里的爱。
It is a great pride, I really miss the club, the city, the people, the love.
Es un orgullo muy grande, que extraño mucho el club, la ciudad, la gente, el cariño.
和往常一样，我希望事情不会继续顺利，我们可以继续让这个俱乐部变得更大。
And nothing, as always, I hope it doesn't continue to go well and we can continue making this club even bigger.
Y nada, como siempre, ojalá no siga yendo bien y podamos seguir haciendo más grande todavía este club.
伟大的巴萨球队，你曾是三四支达到很高水平的球队的一员。
The great Barça teams, you have been part of three or four that have reached very high levels.
Los grandes equipos del Barça, tú has formado parte de tres o cuatro que han llegado muy alto.
他们总是吃得很饱，由来自农舍的球员组成，比如巴萨实际队。
They are always very fed, very formed by players who come from the farmhouse, like Barça Actual, for example.
siempre están muy alimentados, muy formados por jugadores que vienen de la masía, como el Barça Actual, por ejemplo.
你怎么看？
How are you seeing it?
¿Cómo la estás viendo?
我看到它很壮观。
I see it spectacular.
Lo veo espectacular.
这并不让我感到惊讶，因为这不是什么新鲜事，但它在我的一生中都发生过，或者至少自从我参与其中以来。
And it doesn't surprise me, because it's not something that's new, but it's happened all my life, or at least since I've been in it.
Y no me sorprende, porque no es algo que es nuevo, sino que pasó toda la vida, o por lo menos desde que estoy yo en él.
在巴塞罗那，当时他还只有13岁。
in Barcelona, ​​when he is still 13 years old.
en el Barcelona, cuando sigue con 13 años.
我认为孩子们有机会和信心真是太棒了。
And I think it's spectacular that the kids have the opportunity and the confidence.
Y me parece espectacular que los chicos tengan la oportunidad y la confianza.
他们这样回应是因为他们比任何人都更了解俱乐部，因为他们习惯了今天的比赛方式。
They respond this way because they know the club better than anyone, because they are used to playing the way it is played today.
responden de esta manera porque conocen el club mejor que nadie, porque están acostumbrados a jugar de la manera que se juega hoy.
当他还是个孩子的时候，当他陪伴时，就会发生这种情况。
as a child and when he is accompanied it happens.
de chiquito y cuando se lo acompaña sucede.
这些事情的发生就像在另一个时代发生的那样。
These things happen as they happened in another era too.
se suceden estas cosas como sucedió en otra época también.
这也是对我们弥赛亚的认可。
It is also a recognition of Our Messiah.
es también un reconocimiento al Nuestro Mesías.
巴萨125年的历史......
Of the 125 years of history of Barça...
De los 125 años de historia del Barça...
色彩最引以为豪的照片之一。
One of the photos that the colors are most proud of.
Una de las fotos de las que los colores están más orgullosos.
他与哈维和伊涅斯塔一起来自电视金飞行员。
He is from the TV pilota d'or, alongside Xavi and Iniesta.
es de la tele pilota d'or, al costado de Xavi y de Iniesta.
因为他们重视魔法。
because they value magic.
porque valoran la magia.
他们为拥有世界上最好的足球学校而感到自豪。
They are proud to have the best soccer school in the world.
Demostran orgullosos de tener la mejor escuela de fútbol del mundo.
提到魔法你会想起什么？
What do you remember about magic?
¿Qué te recuerdas de la magia?
巨大的对我来说意义重大。
The massive one meant a lot to me.
La masiva para mí significó muchísimo.
作为一名足球运动员，你如何定义自己？
How would you define yourself as a footballer?
¿Cómo te definirías como futbolista?
呃……好吧，我不知道，我无法定义自己。
Eh... Well, I don't know, I can't define myself.
Eh... Bueno, no sé, no me puedo definir yo.
那还是13岁啊。
That's still 13 years old.
Eso sigue con 13 años.
到了俱乐部，我在那里长大并生活得比我在阿根廷的家还要长。
to the club and I grew up and lived there longer than in my own home in Argentina.
al club y crecí y viví más tiempo ahí que en mi propia casa en Argentina.
我是在他们教给我的价值观中长大的，我在......
and I grew up with the values ​​that they taught me, I studied at...
y crecí con los valores que me enseñaron ellos, estudié en la...
在拉马西亚学院，对我来说，我在那里度过的时光至关重要，因为它让我不仅成为一名球员，而且……
at Colegio de la Masía, for me my time there was fundamental because it made me not only as a player, but as...
en el Colegio de la Masía, para mí fue fundamental mi paso por ahí porque me hizo no solo como jugador, sino como...
作为一个人也是如此。
as a person too.
como persona también.
好吧，我们进了五个球，我希望继续进更多球。
Well, we scored five goals and I hope to continue scoring more.
Bien, marcamos cinco goles y espero seguir marcando más.
你是个傻瓜，我明白，对于孩子们和几代足球之手来说，
You are a fool, I understand, for the children and for many generations of football hands,
Tú eres una llisón, yo entiendo, por los niños y por muchas generaciones de manos del fútbol,
我们记得他的伟大表现、伟大进球，但我们也记得他的伟大联想。
a person of whom we remember great plays, great goals, but we also remember great associations.
una persona de la que recordemos grandes jugadas, grandes gols, pero también recordemos grandes asociaciones.
您已经与 Busi 建立了关系并了解了当前团队中的所有队友。
You have formed relationships and have understood all your teammates on the current team, with Busi.
has formado parellas y has entendido a todos tus compañeros del equipo actual, con el Busi.
和阿尔巴，和苏亚雷斯。
with Alba, with Suárez.
con la Alba, con el Suárez.
似乎压倒性的信息是找到另一个人非常重要。
The message that seems to overwhelm is that it is very important to find the other.
El mensaje que parece sobresortir es que es muy importante encontrar al otro.
这就是全部内容，对吧？
That's what it's all about, right?
Eso se trata, ¿no?
都说是那么容易，但有时候做起来又是那么难。
It is said that it is so easy, but sometimes it is so difficult to do it.
Se dice que es tan fácil, pero a veces es tan difícil hacerlo.
一份来自同一团队，一份来自您的合作伙伴，但这就是我们的工作内容。
one from the same team, one from your partner, but that was what we worked on.
a uno de un mismo equipo, a uno de tu compañero, pero eso era lo que trabajábamos nosotros.
日复一日。
the day to day.
el día a día.
事实是，我很幸运能够与最优秀的球员并肩作战，这让一切变得更加......
And then the truth is that I was lucky enough to play alongside the best, which made everything much more...
y después también la verdad que tuve la suerte de jugar con los mejores también al lado, que eso hacía que todo sea mucho más...
也更容易。
easier too.
más fácil también.
谁接了或者谁碰了对方。
Who received or who touched the other side.
Que recibía o el que tocaba del otro lado.
我首先想到了与我要做的相同的意图，然后我很好地执行了它。
I did it first thinking about the same intention as I am going and then I executed it well.
Lo hacía primero pensando en la misma intención que voy y después lo ejecutaba bien.
这显然让一切变得更加容易。
and that obviously made everything easier.
y eso obviamente facilitaba todo.
对我们来说这很简单，因为我们是伴随着它长大的，但来自外面的人却完全不同，全新的。
For us it is simple because we grew up with it, but someone who comes from outside is totally different, totally new.
Para nosotros es sencillo porque crecimos con eso, pero por ahí el que viene de afuera es totalmente diferente, totalmente nuevo.
我有一个适应，它的成本......
and I have an adaptation and it costs...
y llevo una adaptación y cuesta...
起初。
at first.
al principio.
归根结底，这就是足球，但又有所不同。
In the end it is football, but it is different.
Al final es fútbol, pero es diferente.
并不断地与第三人玩耍，占据空间。
and continually play with the third man, occupy the spaces.
y jugar continuamente con el tercer hombre, ocupar los espacios.
我们这些来自那里的人自然会做的事情，我感到非常惊讶
of things that those of us from there do naturally and I was very surprised that
de cosas que lo que somos de ahí lo hacemos naturalmente y me sorprendía mucho que
非常高素质的球员到来，但他们付出了代价。
Very high-quality players arrived and it cost them.
jugadores de muchísima calidad llegaba y le costaba.
在那里你意识到我们如此轻松自然地说的话，
There you realize that what we said so easily and naturally,
ahí te das cuenta de que lo que nosotros decíamos tan fácil y natural,
事情没那么简单。
It wasn't that simple.
No era tan sencillo.
现在我将向您介绍巴萨悠久历史中的三个瞬间。
Now I will give you three moments from the long history of Barça.
Ahora te daré tres momentos del largo recorrido de la historia del Barça.
因为你告诉我一个，你什么时候进入农舍或者什么时候……？
because you tell me one, when do you enter the farmhouse or when...?
porque me en tríes uno, ¿cuándo entras a la masía o cuando...?
或者当你在一线队首次亮相时，我不知道。
or when you debut with the first team, I don't know.
o cuando debutas con el primer equipo, no sé.
卡普在罗马决赛中的进球。
Cap's goal in the final in Rome.
el gol de cap a la final de Roma.
¡贝西·德·卡贝萨！
¡Bessie de cabeza!
贝西头球破门！
Bessie scored with a header!
¡Ha marcado Bessie de cabeza!
第三次是你第一次赢得飞行员。
and the third would be the first time you win the pilot.
y el tercer sería la primera vez que ganas la pilota.
考虑到我在俱乐部的所有历史，事实是很难留在……
With all my history in the club, the truth is that it is difficult to stay with...
Con toda la historia mía en el club, la verdad que es difícil quedarme con...
三个特定时刻。
with three specific moments.
con tres momentos en concreto.
事实上，我会把其中一个或另一个我放在第一位。
In fact I would have put one or the other me first.
De hecho hubiese puesto uno u otro yo por delante.
但出道当天我必须保留一张，对吗？
But I do have to keep one on the day of my debut, right?
Pero si me tengo que quedar con uno el día de mi debut, ¿no?
里奥·梅西将在本赛季首次亮相。
Leo Messi will make his debut this season.
Debutará, Leo Messi, en esta temporada.
他是一个有所作为的孩子。
He is a child who makes a difference.
Es un niño que marca la diferencia.
感谢我为改变国家和改变自己而做出的牺牲。
For the sacrifice I had made to change the country and to change myself.
Por el sacrificio que había hecho yo de cambiar de país y de cambiar mí.
我的生活彻底。
my life completely.
mi vida completamente.
所有人都在寻找那一刻，那一天……
and all in search of that moment, the day of...
y todo en búsqueda de ese momento, del día de...
从我的首次亮相，从在头等舱比赛开始，我认为那是最重要的时刻。
From my debut, from playing in first class, I think that was the most important moment.
de mi debut, de jugar en primera, creo que ese fue el momento más importante.
在您与巴萨的漫长历史中积累的所有记录中，另一个记忆是什么？
And of all the accumulated records that you have in your long history with Barça, what is the other memory?
y de todos los recordes acumulados que tienes en tu larga historia con el Barça, ¿cuál es el otro recuerdo?
当他回忆起在巴萨的时光时，他最喜欢的就是梅西。
favorite of Messi when he remembers his time at Barça.
preferido de Messi cuando recuerda su época en el Barça.
快点！
Come on!
¡Vamos!
我保留的不止一年，对吗？
I keep more than one than the year, right?
Me quedo con más que uno que con el año, ¿no?
Sestete 年我认为那一年是......
The year of the Sestete I think that year was...
El año del Sestete creo que ese año fue...
卢里奥斯。
Lurios.
每天都很享受，训练、比赛。
It was enjoying every day, training, match.
Era disfrutar todos los días, entrenamiento, partido.
我们要出去比赛，知道比赛将如何结束，但我们非常有信心。
It was going out to play and knowing how the game was going to end, but we had so much confidence.
Era salir a jugar y saber cómo iba a terminar el partido, pero teníamos tanta confianza.
赢或者我们要赢，系统就是它的结局。
win or we were going to win, the system was how it was going to end.
ganar o íbamos a ganar, el sistema era cómo iba a terminar.
那是我很享受的一年，我想我们都很享受。
It was a year where I enjoyed that and I think we all enjoyed it.
Fue un año en el que disfruté eso y creo que lo disfrutamos todos.
他们花了多长时间？
How long did they take?
¿Cuánto tiempo llevaron?
多长时间？
How long?
¿Cuánto tiempo?
你必须跨越大西洋，改变国家，适应新的文化。
You have to cross the Atlantic, change countries, adapt to a new culture.
que entrepasar el Atlántico, cambiar de país, adaptarte a una nueva cultura.
现在你又对它有了看法，因为你又生活在美国了。
And now you have perspective on it again, because you live in America again.
Y ahora vuelves a tener perspectiva sobre ello, porque vuelves a vivir en América.
对于您和您在加泰罗尼亚的家人来说有多重要？
How important is it for you and your family in Catalonia?
¿Cómo es importante para ti y para tu familia en Cataluña?
嗯，对我来说，我的生活就是在巴塞罗那，生活......
Well, for me, my life is being in Barcelona, ​​living...
Bueno, para mí, mi vida es estar en Barcelona, vivir...
事实上，在巴塞罗那...
in Barcelona, ​​in fact...
en Barcelona, de hecho...
除了我们必须离开这座城市和加泰罗尼亚这一事实之外。
beyond the fact that we had to leave the city and Catalonia.
más allá de que tuvimos que irnos de la ciudad y de Cataluña.
我们总是想着明天能够再次住在那里。
Tomorrow is always on our minds to be able to live there again.
En nuestra mente siempre está el día de mañana en poder volver a vivir ahí.
我的孩子、我的妻子和我为他带来了很多生活。
My children, my wife and I bring a lot of our lives to him.
Mis hijos, mi mujer y yo le traemos mucho la vida nuestra.
在巴塞罗那，因为我们有朋友，因为我们离开......
in Barcelona because we have friends, because we leave...
en Barcelona porque tenemos amigos, porque dejamos...
已经有很多事情了。
Many things already.
Muchísimas cosas ya.
我的孩子是加泰罗尼亚人。
My children are Catalan.
Mis hijos son catalanes.
我一生都住在那里，事实是我觉得……
And I spent my whole life living there and the truth is that I feel...
Y yo llego toda la vida viviendo ahí y la verdad que yo me siento de...
来自巴塞罗那，非常怀念。
from Barcelona, ​​I miss it very much.
de Barcelona, extraño muchísimo.
你永远不知道生活中会发生什么，但我们的目的是......
You never know what happens in life, but our intention is...
Nunca se sabe que para la vida, pero la intención nuestra es...
住在那里，因为，那是我们的家。
to live there because, well, it is our home.
de vivir ahí porque, bueno, es nuestra casa.